好险
That was close,
我太喜欢清晨彩弹的味道了
God,I love the smell of paintballs in the morning.
还是很搞笑  拉杰
Yeah,still finny,Raj.
没办法去山脊了
There's no way we can get to the ridge.
化学部的人完全把我们堵死了
The chemistry department has us completely cut off.
河床呢
But what about the creek bed?
被药理学部门拿下了
The pharmacology department controls that,
他们全都吃了兴奋剂
And they're all hopped up on experimental steroids.
完了  我们死定了
That's it then. we're doomed.
现在该承认我们会沦落至此
I think the time has come to acknowledge that
就是因为某人没参加
we are paying the price for some of us failing to attend my
我的物理学部门战略会议
Physics department paintball strategy meeting.
我说了  我妈妈得了微血管扩张
I told you my mom has spider veins.
我要带她去激光治疗
I had to take her to the laser clinic.
我也跟你说了  我要看医嘱
And I told you I wanted to see a doctor's note.
我们要定个策略
We need a plan.
-"上帝之锤"怎么样  -我忘了
How about operation hammer of the gods? I forget.
哪个是"上帝之锤"
Which one is hammer of the gods?
我们藏到停车场的垃圾桶后面
We hide behind the dumpsters in the parking
伏击去尿尿的人
Lot and ambush people when they come to pee.
不行
No go.
垃圾桶那边完全是天文学部门的领地
The dumpsters are deep in astronomy department territory.
应该不成问题
That shouldn't be a problem.
金星白天都显现
Venus is up during the day.
他们估计都在望天呢
They're probably just all staring at the sky.
行了  我们现在要战术性撤退
All right, what we need now is a tactical retreat.
你们看了那集《星际之门》吗
Did you see the episode of stargate
他们在一个
where they found themselves on a planet
类似雅典和斯巴达文明的星球上
with a culture based loosely on earth's athens and sparta?
算了
Not important.
莱纳德  拉杰和我一起冲出大门逃跑
Leonard, raj and I are going to burst out the door and run away.
霍华德掩护
Howard will cover us.
为什么不是我逃跑你掩护
Why don't I run away and you cover me?
因为你用胜利来换取带你母亲看病
Because you chose your mother's veins over victory.
数到三
On three.
一  二  三  闪
One, two, three, go!
我必须带她去
I had to take her!
都快到穿泳衣的天气了
It's almost bathing suit weather!
我投降  别开枪
I surrender! don't shoot!
他们从那边走了
They went that way!
霍华德  我是你的队友
Howard, I'm on your team.
莱斯利  谢天谢地
Oh, leslie, thank god.
你们小队的其他人呢
Where's the rest of your squad?
他们把我留下来等死
Ah, they left me here to die.
你的呢
What about yours?
都死了
Dead, all of them.
真遗憾
Sorry.
没必要
Don't be.
都是友军误伤
It was friendly fire.
他们就是不听话
They just wouldn't listen.
我们被包围了
Well, we're surrounded,
只能等着被俘虏
So I guess there's nothing for us to do
或者被干掉了
but wait to be captured or killed.
最难受的是等待
Hmm, that's the worst part, the waiting.
知道有颗带有你的名字的子弹
All the while knowing that there's a
始终会在那里等着你
Paint pellet out there with your name on it.
大大的死亡湿球
Yeah, the big wet ball of death.
更能让你感觉自己还活着  对吧
Kind of makes you feel more alive, doesn't it?
确实
It kind of does.
还是别浪费时间吧
I say we make every moment count.
可以
I agree.
有什么可做的呢
How exactly do we do that?
霍华德  你怎么不掩护我们
Howard, why aren't you covering us?!
我们快被杀光了
We're getting slaughtered out here!
战场就是地狱
War is hell.
你们早上看了新的预算备忘了吗
Did you guys see the new budget memo that went out this morning?
又减少了
Yeah, more cutbacks.
太无法接受了
Unacceptable.
我就想不明白  他们干嘛不直接放弃你们
It baffles me why they don't simply let some of
就有更多钱给我做试验了
You go so that there's money available for my research.
你知道我烦恼什么吗  谢尔顿
You know what baffles me, sheldon?
就你的成绩来看  我看是任何事
Based on your academic record, any number of things, I imagine.
-伙计们  -莱斯利
Hey, guys. hey, leslie. hey.
霍华德  我帮你拿到高速原型机的批准了
Howard, I got the approval for the rapid prototyper you wanted.
太好了  莱斯利  谢谢
That's great, leslie. thanks.
互帮互助而已啦
You scratch my back, I scratch yours.
那是什么意思
What was all that about?
没什么
Oh, uh, no big deal.
他们让莱斯利管一些自由经费
They gave leslie control of some unrestricted grant money.
那挠背和"喵"又是怎么回事
Yeah, okay, but what's with the back- scratching and the meow!
我觉得挠背的隐喻
I believe the back-scratching metaphor
通常指投桃报李的情况
Generally describes a quid pro quo situation where
一方提供物品或服务给另一方
One party provides goods or services to the
报答一种类似之举
Second party in compensation for a similar action.
谢谢
Thank you.
至于"喵"  我感觉听起来像非洲的麝猫
The meow, that sounded to me like an african civet cat.
说完了吗
Are you done?
没有
No.
尽管名字里有猫  但其实麝猫不是真的猫
Despite what the name suggests, the civet cat is not a true cat.
说完了
Now I'm done.
知道我怎么想吗
You know what I'm thinking?
我觉得霍华德并不是用挠背做隐喻
I'm thinking howard wasn't making a back-scratching metaphor.
我觉得确有挠背一说呢
I'm thinking there was some actual scratching involved.
是吗  霍华德
What about it, howard?
我不想说是因为
I didn't want to say anything 'cause I
我知道你和莱斯利以前好过
Know you and leslie have a little history.
我不在乎
I don't care about that.
太好了  我其实早就想说了
Great, 'cause I've been dying to say something?
在彩弹小屋里!  两次!
In the paintball shed! twice!
这就是为什么你没有掩护我们撤退
Is that why you didn't cover our Escape
还让我们像牲口般被屠宰?
and let us get cut down like animals?
对此我非常抱歉
Oh, yeah, sorry about that.
阵前脱逃
Dereliction of duty in the face of the enemy is
是要被送交军事法庭的
a court-martial offense.
管他什么军事法庭[德语]
Court-martial, schmort-martial,
莱斯利·温克尔是第五个和我做过爱的女生
Leslie Winkle is the fifth girl I've ever had sex with.
我是说  不包括付费的
I mean, for free.
而且你还拿到了高速原型机
And plus, you got a rapid prototyper.
老兄 那玩意可不便宜
That's an expensive piece of equipment, dude.
我们剩下的人的预算就被啃到见骨了
And the rest of us have had our budgets cut to the bone.
你可以这样看这个问题
Okay, one way to look at this is that I'm getting new equipment,
我有了新设备  你们没有  这不公平
And you're not, and that's unfair.
更好的角度是 我有女人而你们没有
But a better way to look at this is that I'm getting sex and you're not,
还有什么比这更好
And that's delightful.
所有东西都不响应了
The whole thing froze.
不知道怎么回事
I don't know what happened.
冷静点  能解决的
Calm down. we'll figure it out.
我怎么能冷静得了?
How can I calm down?
我的整个购物车都要被清空了
I'm gonna lose my whole shopping cart.
我选了三个小时的鞋就这么一扫而空了
That's three hours of picking out shoes just shot to hell.
嗨  佩妮
Hello, penny.
嗨  谢尔顿
Hello, sheldon.
你坐在我的专座上了
You're in my spot.
你准备坐这么
Are you planning on sitting here?
不  我要去漫画店
No, I'm going to the comic book store.
那我坐哪有什么区别?
Then what difference does it make?
有什么区别?
What difference does it make?
好戏登场
Here we go.
那是我的专座
That is my spot.
在这个不断变化的世界里  这是不变的一点
In an ever-changing world, it is a single point of consistency.
假设我的生命用一个建立在
If my life were expressed as a function
四维直角坐标系中的方程来表示的话
on a four-dimensional cartesian Coordinate system,
这个座位从我坐上那一刻开始 就成为了 (0,0,0,0)
That spot at the moment I first sat on it would be zero-zero-zero-zero.
你说啥?
What?
不要坐他的专座
Don't sit in his spot.
好吧
Fine.
满意了?
Happy?
我没有不满意
I'm not unhappy.
我爱他 不过他也太极品怪胎了
Boy, I love him, but he is one serious wackadoodle.
好了  电脑修好了
Okay, that should do it.
太感谢了  真是我的恩人
Oh, thank you. you are a lifesaver.
你订了可真不少
That's a lot of shoes you ordered.
可悲的是其实这些对我来说真的不算多了
Yeah, you know the sad thing is, it's really not.
这就是你们的彩弹枪?
Ooh, is this one of those paintball guns?
没错  你下次应该和我们一起来
Yeah. you ought to come out with us sometime.
谢谢  不过还是算了  我从内布拉斯加来
Oh, no, thanks. I'm from nebraska.
在那里  当我们对什么东西开枪的时候 要么是我们要吃它们
When we shoot things, it's because we want to eat them
要么是让他们别妨碍我和男友办事
or make them leave our boyfriends alone.
孩子  你心跳在狂飙 我果然魅力无边啊
Boy, your heart's racing. I must've really gotten you going.
一半是你的原因   一半是我先天就心律紊乱
Well, it's partly you, partly my transient idiopathic arrhythmia.
真性感
Sexy.
那么我可以假定你的感受是
Can I assume that you likewise found the experience...
你满足了我
Satisfactory?
这不是我原本打算的措辞  不过当然
That wasn't quite the word I was looking for, but sure,
我知道我合格了
I'll do this pass-fail.
你觉得我给你弄的那个原型机如何啊
Hey, are you enjoying that prototyper I got you?
很赞啊
Oh, it's great.
工程院里的每个人 都羡慕得要命
Everybody in the engineering department is eating their hearts out.
你很幸运使得旁人痛苦万分的感觉很好吧
Isn't it nice when your good fortune makes others miserable?
一般人理解不了
You know, most people don't get that.
霍华德  我回来了
Howard, I'm home!
好极了
Oh, great.
读书俱乐部的活动取消了
Book club was cancelled!
叶太太颈椎又出问题了
That thing on phyll's neck opened up again!
我忙着呢  老妈
I'm busy, ma!
忙到不能帮妈妈把拉链解开啊
Too busy to help your mother with her zipper?!
您别进来
Don't come in, ma!
为什么
Why not?
他有客人在
He's got company!
又开始心律紊乱了
Oh, there's the arrhythmia.
她是犹太人嘛
Is she jewish?!
你是犹太人么
Are you jewish?
-不是  -是的
- No. - yes!
那行  你们好好玩
Okay, then you kids have fun!
别忘了防护措施
Use protection!
你觉得他会注意到吗
You think he'll notice?
有这种可能
There's a chance.
那我们怎么办
Oh, what are we gonna do?
"我们?"
"we"?
你错了  曾经有一个我们的机会摆在你面前
No, no, you had your chance to be "we"
就在一年半以前
For, like, a year and a half now.
现在  你是你  你完蛋了
Right now, you are "you," and you are screwed.
我们为什么要告诉他是我干的
Why do we have to tell him I did it?
因为我们不会告诉他是我干的
Well, we're not gonna tell him I did it.
这样行么
Okay, okay, how about this?
我们告诉他有人闯进来
We tell him somebody broke in.
就为了向沙发上射击彩蛋
Just to shoot the couch with a paintball gun?
不好意思  我就会相信
I'm sorry, I buy it.
现在嗑药的那么多
All those people are on drugs.
我们可以告诉他
We could tell him
他们想要这个沙发别打扰和男友办事
they wanted the couch to stay away from their boyfriend.
好吧
Okay, fine.
我们把它翻过来不就行了?
What if we just flip it over?
不错吧
There. looks fine, right?
坐印
Mm, butt print.
没有明显的坐印
There's no discernible butt print.
拜托
Oh, come on.
好了  坐印
There, butt print.
太小  太...
It's too small and too...
漂亮了
Perfect.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
嘘  自然点
Shh. act normal.
谢尔顿
Sheldon!
漫画店逛得怎么样
How was the comic book store?
还不错  新一期的《闪电侠》来了
Fine. the new issue of flash is out.
很好  很好  你走回来的吗
Great, great. did you walk the whole way?
外面有点冷
It's a little chilly.
库什帕利送我回来的
Kooth Rappali picked me up.
不是很棒吗
Isn't that terrific?
他真是个好朋友
He is such a good friend.
知道有朋友的最大好处是什么吗
You know what the best thing about friends is?
他们不会无来由地说个不停
They don't talk incessaly for no particular reason.
不  不  朋友之间会宽容小错误的
No, no, friends forgive the little things.
我得回去洗头了
You know, I gotta go home and wash my hair.
你敢  小姐
Don't you dare, missy.
你好  闪电侠
Hello, fastest man alive.
想观赏我看完你的整本漫画书吗
Want to see me read your entire comic book?
要再看一次
Want to see it again?
有点不对劲
Something's wrong.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我也说不上
I'm not sure.
就是感觉不对
It doesn't feel right.
不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
那个  佩妮干的
Oh, that. Penny did that.
抱歉
Excuse me.
你怎么不坐在办公椅那吃
Why don't you just eat in your desk chair?
我怎么不坐在办公椅那吃?
Why don't I just eat in my desk chair?
开始了
Here we go.
那是我的办公椅
That is my desk chair.
是我工作的地方
That is where I work.
我不在办公椅那吃饭  也不在专座上工作
I don't eat in my desk chair and I don't work in my spot.
我在办公椅那工作  在专座上吃饭
I work in my desk chair and eat in my spot.
非常怪胎
Wackadoodle.
有个简单的解决办法
You know, there's kind of an obvious solution here.
起来
Get up.
好了  问题解决
There. problem solved.
没人关心你要坐在哪
Nobody cares where you're going to sit.
你又不疯
You're not crazy.
抱歉  但问题并没解决
Excuse me, but the problem is not solved.
如你的脑袋不小心被截掉了
If your head had been accidentally amputated,
安个狗的脑袋在上面
And we transplanted a dog's head in its place,
这叫"问题解决"吗
Would that be "problem solved"?
如是你的脑袋  问题就解决了
If it were your head, it would be.
谢尔顿  我很  很抱歉  但就一周
Sheldon, I am really, really sorry, but it's only for a week.
你就不能通融点
Can't you be a little bit flexible?
好了  抱歉  我没细想
Yeah, sorry. I didn't really think that through.
你声称说一周就好
You claimed it's going to be a week,
但我对你选的干洗店没信心
But I have no faith in your dry cleaner.
为什么没有
Why not?
你注意到他柜台上的标志了吗
Did you notice the sign on his counter?
他不是全职干干洗的
He's not a full-time dry cleaner.
他还配钥匙
He also makes keys.
看到老天的份上  谢尔顿
Oh, for god's sake, Sheldon.
专注是很重要的
Focus is important.
迈克尔·德倍基[心脏手术创始人]做心脏移植手术之余
Was Michael Debakey a wedding planner
做婚礼策划吗
in between heart transplants?
亚历山大·弗莱明午夜会变身理发师吗
Did Alexander Fleming moonlight as a hairdresser?
"谢谢你发现了青霉素"
"thanks for discovering penicillin.
"来个蓬蓬头吧"
Now how about we try a bouffant?"
看起来我今晚要有"性"福了
Ooh, looks like I'm gonna have sex tonight.
宝贝...
Hey, baby...
他右手在召唤他吗
His right hand is calling him?
不  是莱斯利·温克尔
No, it's Leslie Winkle.
有一段时间了
It's a long story.
我十分钟后接你
I'll pick you up in ten minutes.
各位  再见[法语]
Gentlemen, adieu.
我以为今晚我们要玩《光环》
I thought we were going to play halo tonight.
要我怎么做  莱纳德
What am I supposed to do, Leonard?
有女人在那饥渴地想和我做爱
There's a woman out there anxious to have sex with me.
你明白  对吧
You understand, right?
不  一点都不
No. not at all.
不管怎样  我得走了
Nevertheless, I must depart.
对了  我说过吗
By the way, did I tell you?
莱斯利"活动"了一下  让我参加日内瓦研究之旅
Leslie pulled some strings and got me on the
观测欧洲原子核研究委员会的超级对撞机
Research trip to geneva to check out the cern supercollider.
真不公平
That's not fair.
你甚至不是物理学家
You're not even a physicist.
好了  有两个角度看到这个问题
Okay, there are two ways of looking at this...
出去
Get out.
拜
Bye.
你有提高
You're improving.
谢谢
Thank you.
真人实战确实有助于提高
It helps when I get to practice with a real woman.
听着
Hey, listen.
周六我姐结婚
Saturday my sister's getting married.
我想你陪我去
I-i want you to come with me.
要求宾客穿半正式礼服的
It's black tie.
天  我真的不想去
Yeah, gee, I'd really rather not.
为什么不
Why not?
我去婚礼时  一般都骗骗搞搞胖伴娘
When I go to weddings, it's to scam on chunky bridesmaids.
有约的人了  我不知该怎么做
I don't know what I would do with a date.
好的  我理解
Oh, all right. I understand.
谢了
Thanks.
对了  你去不了日内瓦那件事我真抱歉
Hey, I'm really sorry about that geneva trip.
你说什么呐
What about it?
你不知道吗
Oh, didn't you hear?
我得减少去的人数
I had to reduce the number of people going
然后你就被刷下来了
and you didn't make the cut.
什么时候
When did that happen?
大约12秒之前
About 12 seconds ago.
等等
Well, hold on.
你是说 我要是不去那婚礼就不能去日内瓦了
Are you saying if I don't go to the wedding, I can't go to geneva?
我真不想这么说出来
Actually, I'm trying not to say it.
抱歉但是这让我感到有点不舒服
Okay, I'm sorry, but that makes me a little uncomfortable.
怎么
How so?
这样看起来好像你在
Because it's like you're controlling
用研究旅行和新设备来控制我
Me with new equipment and research trips.
如果我不这样控制你的话
Well, if I weren't controlling you with
我会不舒服
new equipment and research trips, Then I'd be uncomfortable.
为什么
How so?
这样就会弄得像
'cause then we'd be in, like,
我们是来真的一样
A real relationship with feelings and all that crap.
那说到底  我不就是一个你买来玩的性爱玩具嘛
So, bottom line, I'm just a bought-and-paid-for sex toy.
不不  也不全是
No. no, not at all.
你也算是个尤物了
You're also arm candy.
怎么样
So?
你怎么看
What do you think?
妈我要借一套礼服
Hey, ma, you got to rent me a tux!
现在就要?
Right now?
你做什么爱还要用正装的
What kind of sex are you having up there?
你干嘛蹲在那里
Why are you crouching there?
这是我的专座
This is my spot.
我还能蹲哪里
Where else am I supposed to crouch?
我不知道  你老家?
I don't know. texas?
又来了
Here you go.
刚刚从干洗店里拿来的  像新的一样
Fresh from the cleaners, good as new.
真的吗  太好了
Really? great.
谢尔顿  看  焕然一新
Sheldon, look. good as new.
从那个配钥匙店   我严重怀疑
From that key maker, I highly doubt it.
拜托  谢尔顿
Come on, sheldon.
试了再说
Just give it a try.
好吧
All right.
好了  舒舒服服的 (0,0,0)
There, nice and comfy cozy. zero, zero, zero.
还有一个零
There's one more zero.
你忘掉了时间坐标
You forgot the time parameter.
给我坐下
Sit on the damn couch.
不行
Nope.
什么意思  不行 这有什么问题啊
What do you mean, "nope"? What's wrong with it?
这没问题  他有问题
Nothing, it's what's wrong with him.
这两个完全一样的好不好
It's exactly the same...
佩妮  佩妮  让我来搞定好了
Penny, penny, I think I know what to do.
谢尔顿  我要告诉你一些坏消息
Sheldon, I have some bad news.
还有
More?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
你礼拜一的腰果鸡丁
You know the cashew chicken I get you monday nights?
是的  四川宫的
Yes. from szechuan palace.
四川宫两年前倒闭了
Szechuan palace closed two years ago.
什么
What?
那我的鸡丁哪里来的
Where did my cashew chicken come from?
金龙饭店
Golden dragon.
不
No.
不  这不可能的
No, this isn't right.
外卖盒子一直是四川宫的
Our food always comes in szechuan palace containers.
他们倒闭的时候
Yeah, well, before they went out of business,
我买了四千个他们的盒子
I bought 4,000 containers.
然后藏在我车子后面
I keep them in the trunk of my car.
但是
But...
天哪  一切都不同了
Oh, this changes everything.
我觉得这样他就不会去想坐垫
I thought that might take his mind off the cushion.
什么是真实  什么是虚假
What's real? what isn't?
我怎么才能知道
How can I know?
你编故事的是不
You did make that up, right?
我倒希望是编的
Oh, god, I wish I had.
莱纳德?
Leonard?
怎么老兄
Yeah, buddy?
我还是不喜欢这个垫子
I still don't like this cushion.
首先  佩妮感谢你能加入我们
Ok first of all, penny, thank you for coming.
谢谢你买的鞋子
Thanks for the shoes.
佩妮射击很牛叉
Penny is an amazing shot.
我想我们这次很可能会赢
I think we have a real chance to win this week.
什么策略
What's the plan?
好  我们先跑出去
Okay. now, we all run out.
谢尔顿和我在树那边切断他们的左路
Sheldon and I will cut to the left behind these trees.
拉杰 和霍华德 还有莱斯利
Raj, howard and leslie
你们从石头后面包抄
flank to the right behind the rocks.
这样佩妮的视野就开阔了
Then we'll all have a great view as penny
然后她把视野内所有敌人消灭
Runs out and kills everyone else in sight.
我们开始前还有一件事
Just one thing before we start.
什么  谢尔顿
What is it, sheldon?
搞什么
What the hell?!
这是为我的坐垫
That was for my cushion.
谢尔顿  佩妮是我们唯一的希望
Sheldon, penny was our only hope.
对不起莱纳德
I'm sorry, leonard.
君子报仇十年不晚
But revenge is a dish best served cold.
去你的
Screw that.
她不能射我  她已经死了
She can't shoot me. she's dead.
是的  你不能
He's right. you can't.
好  如果我们要堕入无政府主义混乱的话...
Well, if we're going to descend into anarchy...
你们慢慢打  我们先走了
Okay, see you.
等等你们去哪儿
Where are you going?
投降  然后午饭
Surrender, then denny's.